tommiecopper.com 2019-04-09

# Privacy Policy

**Overview**

This privacy policy governs the manner in which Tommie Copper collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a "User" or “you”) of the www.tommiecopper.com Website ("Website"), irrespective of where the User is located. This privacy policy applies to the Website and all products and services offered by Tommie Copper. Please note that the Website may contain links to other third party websites that are not controlled or operated by Tommie Copper. This Privacy Policy does not apply to such third party websites, and Tommie Copper is not responsible for the content of such third party websites or the privacy practices of such parties.

  **Personal identification information**

  We may collect personal identification information from Users in a variety of ways including in the course of the following activities:

  * Visiting our Website.
  * Registering on the Website.
  * Place an order on the Website.
  * Subscribing to the newsletter.
  * Providing product feedback.
  * Participating in consumer contests, sweepstakes or other promotions.
  * Responding to a survey or requests for user’s opinions, concerns, and preferences regarding Tommie Copper products.
  * Filling out a form. This includes information you may provide when you request additional information about Tommie Copper products or services.
  * Using any other features of the Website that may be offered from time to time and may require such information in order to utilize the feature.

Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address, mailing address, phone number, credit card information, and any other information you may chose to provide. If you provide us with your phone number and consent to text marketing, you agree to receive text messages to that number from Tommie Copper. If you submit your email address in connection with an order or request, you agree that Tommie Copper and its third-party service providers may use your email address to contact you about the status of your order or request and for other administrative purposes.

We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personal identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Website related activities. If at any time, you do not wish to receive communications from Tommie Copper, you can unsubscribe from such communications by using the unsubscribe function located on every promotional email or by contacting us at [info@tommiecopper.com](mailto:info@tommiecopper.com). You may also request to have any personal identification information provided to us deleted by emailing [info@tommiecopper.com](mailto:info@tommiecopper.com).

**Non-personal identification information**   

We may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Website. Non-personal identification information may include, but is not limited to, demographic information, precise location information from GPS, cell tower proximity, browser information, type of computer and technical information about Users' means of connection to our Website, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information. This non-personal information is aggregated by using certain tools and mechanisms such as the use of cookies or collection of IP addresses and is kept and used in aggregate form, unless stated otherwise.

We do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from users under 18. Please see our Terms of Use [_https://www.tommiecopper.com/terms-of-use_](https://www.tommiecopper.com/terms-of-use)

**Web browser cookies**

  Our Website may use "cookies" to enhance User experience. User's web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. User may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If they do so, note that some parts of the Website may not function properly.

  **How we use collected information**

  Tommie Copper collects and uses Users' personal information for the following purposes:

  * **To improve our Site:** We continually strive to improve our Website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you. We also use applications provided by third parties, such as Google Analytics, to evaluate the usage of our Website. These tools help us improve the user experience and performance of our Website.
  * **To improve customer service:** Your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs.
  * **To process transactions:** We may use the information Users provide about themselves when placing an order only to provide service to that order. We do not share this information with outside parties except to the extent necessary to provide the service.
  * **To send periodic emails:** The email address a User provides for order processing, will only be used to send them information and updates pertaining to their order. It may also be used to respond to their inquiries, and/or other requests or questions. If a User decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions in each email we send you.
  * To process transactions and purchases that you make on the Website, or through the Website.
  * **To protect our rights or comply with law -** We may disclose personal identification information to enforce our rights arising from any contracts entered into between you and Tommie Copper; to comply with any court order, legal process, or respond to any governmental or regulatory request; or to protect Tommie Copper’s rights or property or the safety of Tommie Copper, our customers, employees, or others.
  * **Sale or merger -** We also may disclose personal identification information to a buyer or other successor in the event of a merger, acquisition, divestiture, restructuring, reorganization, dissolution, or other sale or transfer of Tommie Copper’s assets.

**How we protect your information**

We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices, and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Website. Sensitive and private data exchange between the Website and its Users happens over a SSL secured communication channel and is encrypted and protected with digital signatures. While we use security measures to protect sensitive and personal information transmitted online, please be aware that no security measures are perfect or impenetrable. If you have any questions about the security of personal information collected by Tommie Copper, please contact: [info@tommiecopper.com](mailto:info@tommiecopper.com).

  **Sharing your personal information**

  We do not sell, trade, or rent Users' personal identification information to others. 

Tommie Copper may disclose your personal information to its subsidiaries and affiliates and to third parties whom Tommie Copper hires to provide services on Tommie Copper’s behalf, including but not limited to, support services, Website services, delivering promotional materials, contests and answering customer questions about products. Tommie Copper will only provide those third parties with the personal information that they need to deliver the services to Tommie Copper and/or on Tommie Copper’s behalf. We share your payment information, including your credit or debit card number, card expiration date, CVV code, and billing address with payment service providers to process payments; prevent, detect and investigate fraud or other prohibited activities, or for other purposes associated with the use of credit or debit cards.

We may share or disclose non-personal, generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above. Tommie Copper will only provide those third parties with the information that they need to deliver services to Tommie Copper and on Tommie Copper’s behalf. Notwithstanding anything to the contrary in this Privacy Policy, we may disclose your information if we believe it is reasonably necessary to comply with a law, regulation, legal process or government request; to protect the safety of any individual; to address fraud, security or technical issues; to protect our or other users’ rights or property.

**Accessing your personal information**

You may log in to Tommie Copper to update your registration information.

**Your California Privacy Rights and Choices**

Because we value your privacy, we will not provide personal identification information about you to third parties for their solicitation or marketing purposes.

California law permits Users who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to the contact information below with "California Shine the Light Privacy Request" in the subject line and your full name, email address, postal address and specific services you have used in the body of your email.

**Children’s information**

Our Site is not directed to children under the age of 13, and our Terms prohibit children under 13 from using our Site. We do not knowingly collect any information from children under 13.

**U.S. Website and European Data Protection Rights**

Tommie Copper operates in the United States of America under U.S. law. Any information you choose to send to this Site or Tommie Copper will be subject to the laws of the United States. If you do not wish your information to subject to U.S. law, please do not send it to Tommie Copper.

Tommie Copper will protect the personal identification information of non-U.S. visitors in the same way as it does U.S. visitors. Some jurisdictions, such as the European Union, do not consider the U.S. legal system to offer privacy and data protections that are “adequate” in their judgment, and require us to warn you about their determination.

Should any European visitor wish to have access to, correct, modify, delete or dispute any personal identification information that Tommie Copper holds about them, please contact us using the information below.

Tommie Copper does not intend to offer its product or Services in any jurisdiction where the offering of such products or Services would be contrary to applicable local law, and any such offer of products or Services is void if illegal under applicable law.

**Changes to this privacy policy**

  Tommie Copper has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. The most current version of the policy will govern our use of your information and will always be at [_https://www.tommiecopper.com/privacy-policy_](https://www.tommiecopper.com/privacy-policy/). When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.  
** **   
**Your acceptance of these terms**

  By using this Website, you signify your acceptance of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Website. Your continued use of the Website following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

  **Contacting us**

  If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this Website, or your dealings with this Website, please contact us at:

**Tommie Copper  
 **www.tommiecopper.com  
 **74 S. Moger Ave.  
 **Mount Kisco, NY 10549  
 **1-855-692-8291
